

Kaustav Dutta Application Solution Developer

kaustavpo12@gmail.com

+4915145846026

, 9

Mannheim, Germany

linkedin.com/in/kaustav-dutta in

github.com/kaustavdutta1989 🦪

Agile, result-oriented developer with 8+ years of development and management experience in providing integrated application design implementation testing release & maintenance solutions to diverse clients globally, including banking and established organizations. Record of success in managing clients through niche companies in Web and Mobile Applications with REST and Cloud Infrastructures. Javascript backend development with various integrations and realizations.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Associate Software Engineer EVRY India

07/2012 - 09/2015 Bangalore, India

Achievements/Tasks

- Led Agile Sprint Teams for Banking, Finance & Payments Development of REST / SOAP Microservices with Java 8 Springboot.
- Release Management with Snapshot Dependency upon Cloud Repositories at GIT or SVN with Maven Packaging.
- Record Breaking Unit Test Code Coverage with 95-98% upon Cobertura for API & DAO Microservices.
- Game Animation Design with Javascript, HTML & CSS for Learning Mobile or Web Application Solutions.

Senior Software Engineer

Price Waterhouse Coopers SDC

10/2015 - 09/2018

Bangalore, India

- Achievements/Tasks
- Led the Integration and Data Migration Agile Teams for Banking, Security and Payment Industries.
- Conceptualised, Designed, Developed, Tested, Released, Maintained Mobile & Web Applications.
- Requirement & Quality Analysis for Clients in Warranty Periods of Integration & Smoke Testing.
- Automated 80% Data Migration using Salesforce Tool and XML Batching for Continuous Integration.

Working Student Product Engineer

BIM Systems Ltd

07/2019 - 01/2020

Stuttgart, Germany

Achievements/Tasks

- Managed Code Structure Management for data migration Nemetschek into JSON/XML for Product Details Integration.
- Increased Application Code Quality and Infrastructure for 20% of the CAD BIM Integration with C++ and DLLs.
- Prepared language dependent Dynamic Link Library for Application in English, German, French & Spanish.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Working Student Product Developer

BorgWarner

02/2020 - 09/2020 kirchheimbolanden, Germany

- Achievements/Tasks
- Solely designed, developed, tested and released Compressor Mapping Tool for Turbo-Engine R&D data plot.
- Automated Compressor Tool with Excel, VBA, Uni-Plot Batching and Compressor Map Plotting Template.
- Reduced the Turbo-Engine R&D data analysis time from 28mins to 12 mins for the Turbo Charger Testing Process.

Cross Cloud DeveloperBirkenstock Digital GmbH

05/2021 - Bis jetzt Munich, Germany

- Special achievements/responsibility
- Developed Multi-Country/Local In-house Sites with Salesforce Commerce Cloud in Javascript & ISML.
- Integrated (3rd party) Coupons, Emails, Notifications & Account updates with SFCC & Salesforce Marketing Cloud.
- Collaborated SFCC with Salesforce Service Cloud for Customer Experience with Chats & Emails.
- Interaction with OSMS and managing the Updates from the External System into Order Management.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Programming Skill Learning Game (02/2020 - 09/2020)

- A Game to Learn Basic Programming Skills & C # Backend with Unity-2D Gaming Engine.
- Concept, Design & Implementation of Gaming Scenarios and Scalable & Maintainable Serious Game.

Doctor's Appointment Application (01/2019 - 02/2019)

- Application for Doctors & Patients to Manage Appointments & REST API Data Flow from MySQL Database with Kubernetes.
- Java 9 Spring Boot Microservices to Control Application Flow & AngularJS frontend for Interactive User Experience.

World Democracy - NoSQL Databases (10/2019 - 12/2019)

- Database Structure of World Democracy based on 5 Major Democratic Aspects for Major 121 Countries upon Last 100 Years of Democracy Status.
- MongoDB to Dump all kinds of Data comprising Media, Non-Media, Tables, Etc. and Redis Database to manage user traffic data.
- Neo4J to Create Relations between Countries, Democratic Periods upon 5 Democratic Aspects with the supporting Data.

Task Management Tool (04/2019 - 06/2019)

- Application to Manage Tasks in Projects with Issues and Log Time & Angular 7 with ThymeLeaf, NodeJS Javascript Framework.
- Java 9 Microservices with Spring Boot & MySQL Database and HTTP Web Services for Data Flow from Database Docker Containers.

CERTIFICATES

Salesforce Certified Administrator (10/2015 - 09/2019)

Platform Developer I (10/2015 - 09/2019)

Platform Developer II (10/2016 - 09/2019)

Sales Cloud Consultant (04/2015 - 09/2019)

EDUCATION

Masters in Science SRH Heidelberg Germany

10/2018 - 09/2020

1.8 CTS

- Modules
- Software Development Practice Doctors Appointment Application for doctors & patients with Java & Angularjs.
- Software Architecture & Development Project & Story Management Application with Angular & REST.
- Developing Mobile Applications Personal Food & Grocery Management Application with C# & Xamarin.
- Advanced Database Systems World Democracy Relational Design with MongoDB & Neo4J.
- Applied Artificial Intelligence Alexa & ESP8266 Chatbot with Python & AWS for Home Automation.
- Thesis Developing Scalable & Maintainable Serious Games for Learning Basics of Programming.

EDUCATION

O Bachelors of Engineering

Visvesvaraya Technological University

09/2008 - 06/2012

Tumkur, Karnataka, India

courses

Final Year Project: Hybrid Battery Car Ignition.

- Assembly Level Programming with MCU/MPU.

LANGUAGES

English

German

Full Professional Proficiency

Elementary Proficiency